= kisskh.lv =
♪ From primal chaos to the starry sky ♪
♪ In the whole world, we shall hold the balance ♪
♪ The cauldron tempers divine blades ♪
♪ The furnace refines the empty void ♪
♪ The Way is in mystic fate ♪
♪ Be brave enough to split the primal chaos wide open ♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
[Eve of Li Changshou's Tribulation]
So many clouds up here.
That is...
Changgeng?
No wonder Fate didn't strike me down.
He's a ruthless one.
Bear with it a moment.
The Pregenesis Sword.
[Episode 16]
This Tribulation bearer
looks like Changgeng.
Changgeng is but a mask.
No wonder we couldn't find him.
Did you see his face?
That was the Divine-Demon Tribulation.
I couldn't get anywhere near it.
But I saw Changgeng
take out the Pregenesis Sword.
After he left Bear Island,
he went straight into the Tribulation.
So, he must've gotten the magic instrument.
That's why his power surged.
Now that he's survived the Tribulation,
his power must've grown enormously.
If we don't deal with him now,
sooner or later,
he'll be a grave threat to the Westdawn Sect.
More importantly,
we must take the Pregenesis Sword from him.
The Westdawn Sect's plan spans a thousand years.
The Two Saints await us to open the East Sea's Eye.
Easier said than done.
Where can we find his true form?
Changgeng first appeared
in the Dragon Palace of the East Sea.
There was only one route in and out.
That means.
Changgeng's true form
was among those in the palace then.
If he's not from the Dragon Clan,
he must be from the Ascendance Sect.
Changgeng is a fearsome foe,
but he has things he fears.
He used this mask
to keep us from finding his true form.
Then,
there must be a reason.
We'll expose what he fears
and force a flaw to show.
How do you plan to do that?
Lord Bian,
you might reveal his mask
and tell everyone
that the cultivator who survived
the Divine-Demon Tribulation is Changgeng.
What do you mean?
Next,
point Changgeng's identity toward the Ascendance Sect.
Wen Jing,
you asked me for a plan.
It's time to set it in motion.
Are you sure?
The Westdawn Sect's thousand-year plan
is just one step away.
We must find Changgeng
and seize the Pregenesis Sword,
no matter the cost.
[Anshui City, Donglin Kingdom]
The Sea Deity
can grant great power!
If you want it,
come and find Xiong Lingli.
The Sea Deity
can grant great power!
If you want it,
come and find Xiong Lingli.
Take a look at the Sea Deity Sect.
The Sea Deity Sect.
Come and find Xiong Lingli.
The Sea Deity can grant great power!
If you want it, come and find Xiong Lingli.
[The Sea Deity can grant great power]
Sir, do you want in?
The Sea Deity Sect?
The Sea Deity can grant great power!
Bro, join us.
Our Grandlord Changgeng
is a true deity.
Changgeng?
Could it be the Changgeng
who faced Tribulation in the South Sea?
You know our deity?
A deity's Tribulation is rare.
Word has spread these days.
I heard that Changgeng
is a Qi refiner from Ascendance Sect.
Do you know the way to Ascendance Sect?
It's in the Divine Land.
Everyone, follow me.
Everyone, hurry, follow me!
I've found the deity!
The Sea Deity...
Deity, I'm coming!
Can grant great power!
Deity!
The Sea Deity...
Deity, I'm coming!
Can grant great power!
Deity!
[Good Luck, Certain Victory]
This Tribulation is too showy.
It will surely spark new karma
and bring even more calamity.
I must account for every change.
With your skill,
why hide yourself away?
You could show your talent
and make your name among cultivators.
That will not do.
The Great Tribulation
is almost upon us.
I cannot be noticed now.
The Westdawn Sect is after me.
My paper butterflies found
that someone has spread rumors,
claiming Changgeng caused this Tribulation,
and that Changgeng
is hiding in Ascendance Sect.
Good.
Good?
How is that good?
Back on Bear Island,
you helped me plan.
Now, it's my turn.
Yunxiao, any plan?
It's quite simple.
You only need to admit that you're Changgeng.
Westdawn Sect hides in the dark.
If we can't catch them,
we'll stay on the back foot.
Now, they have recognized you.
Just claim your identity.
That will bring them out.
Rest assured.
With my help,
I will keep you safe.
Once we catch a Westdawn Sect man,
we can trace the clue
and bring down Westdawn Sect.
Then we can stop the Great Tribulation.
Yunxiao.
Well.
Have you misunderstood me?
What?
I can't claim that identity.
You...
I've arranged the Dragon Clan's ascension plan
for the Celestial Court.
But I accidentally
stripped Ao Yi of all his spiritual energy.
So, I must help him regain his strength
and return to the Dragon Palace,
so I can finish the ascension plan.
What about the Westdawn Sect?
They're triggering the Great Tribulation,
yet you're focused on your ascension plan.
Right now,
the best outcome is letting the Celestial Court
step into Dragon Palace affairs.
Yunxiao, don't be so hasty.
I am being hasty.
You leave nothing to chance.
Yunxiao.
We still do not know
how far Westdawn Sect has spread.
So we cannot act rashly.
Did you not say they've infiltrated
the Ascendance Sect?
Let's just start with Ascendance Sect
and root out Westdawn Sect entirely.
You make it sound so easy.
But...
You are unwilling?
It is not that.
This matter
needs a longer plan
and full preparation, right?
Then, you can
take your time preparing.
Yunxiao.
I...
It's been so long.
Senior surely misses me.
This time, I'll win him over.
Don't go.
What?
He's talking about me.
Yunxiao, don't go.
Don't go, Yunxiao.
Mentor.
Wait. What are you two doing here?
What do you mean?
You trapped me here for so long
and came back with no apology.
You just hid here to nap.
Junior already came to save you.
Junior?
You told her you were visiting kin.
Visiting kin?
What relatives do you have?
Goat relatives in the mountains?
Or monkey relatives?
Mentor, you've misunderstood.
Alright, stop making things up.
I won't believe a word of it.
I can't be bothered to spin tales.
You're lovesick, aren't you?
Mentor, what are you talking about?
Don't explain. You're young.
I know all too well.
I just fear you'll make a mistake.
Haven't you blundered enough before?
No, Mentor.
No, don't, please don't.
Don't pick up the whip.
Flowers
can bloom again,
but youth
never returns.
Cherish those around you.
Actually,
I also once had
an unforgettable love.
It wasn't in spring.
It was in late autumn.
She and I...
Changshou!
The mood is at its peak.
Let me finish!
It was
in late autumn.
[Hall of United Spirits]
Disciple...
Mentor,
I'm Qi Yuan.
Today, I vow to make Ascendance Sect my home.
I will cultivate the Way.
[Wan Jiangyu] and guard here forever.
Good, good.
I'm Wan Jiangyu.
I'll also make Ascendance Sect my home.
I will cultivate the Way and guard here forever.
[Jade Division]
What is this?
Tomorrow, you'll go to the Training Assembly.
Your cultivation is still shallow.
You may not beat those beasts.
So, I made this amulet.
It's the Training Assembly.
Mentor sent us to train there.
How can you help me?
Even if I win, it would be unseemly.
I do not want it.
How can you do that?
Do not worry.
I will win for sure.
You fool.
Come on, come on.
Senior!
I'll win this time.
[Tablets of past Ascendance Grand lords]
May Junior Qi Yuan do us proud
and pass the Training Assembly.
Senior.
Qi Yuan! Qi Yuan!
Senior!
Qi Yuan!
What happened?
Wasn't he at the Training Assembly?
How was he injured?
He had an accident there.
His foundation is ruined.
He has no hope of ascending to immortality.
Qi Yuan.
Senior,
I let you down.
Senior.
Junior Qi Yuan.
After we part today,
we may never meet again?
You are gifted,
a first-rate immortal seedling.
I once hoped to cultivate and ascend
to immortality with you,
but now your foundation is ruined.
That's made you an ordinary man.
I...
How could I bear such a thing?
Mentor and I have decided to leave
and search the world
for herbs to mend your foundation.
Qi Yuan,
wait for me.
I'll cure you.
Senior!
[Jade Division]
Senior.
Speak.
I've figured it out.
Although this Tribulation is too showy,
the outside world doesn't know
the true Tribulation bearer is me.
But I know.
Except for you.
In that case,
I just need to steer this a bit
and direct the bearer's identity elsewhere.
That'll give me some room to maneuver.
How about it?
Who should you direct it to?
This person
must stay far from me.
They can't be from Ascendance Sect.
How about...
How about I say it's an Elucidating Sect immortal
out for the Tribulation?
Senior!
What is it, Junior?
Cloudlink Hermit from the Elucidating Sect is here.
Mentor wants to see you.
The Elucidating Sect?
When the Three Sages attained the Way,
the Primeval Lord of Heaven founded the Elucidating Sect.
That sect
is very strict in taking disciples.
Only those truly blessed may enter.
Don't let the small number fool you.
They have Empyreal Aureate Immortals.
How are they so powerful?
They hand-pick immortal seedlings as disciples
and then feed them spirit elixirs
and treasure pearls.
And then...
So...
That's basically cheating.
The Grandlord has arrived.
Greetings, Grandlord.
Sir,
forgive me for not greeting you sooner.
I'm Cloudlink Hermit of Jadevoid Palace.
[Cloudlink Hermit, Elucidating Sect]
Nice to see you.
What brings you
here today?
A few days ago,
a cultivator underwent Divine-Demon Tribulation
in the South Sea.
This man is said
to be called Changgeng - Why does he
- of the Ascendance Sect.
- Only greet the Grandlord?
The Divine-Demon Tribulation - That's perfectly normal.
- Hasn't appeared in a thousand years.
- The Elucidating Sect disciples.
- This one must be gifted.
- Tend to be proud and aloof.
My mentor doesn't want you - Only Aureate Immortals
- to lead him astray.
- Worth their time.
So, I was sent to assess this man
and see if he's worthy of our sect.
Among all of our disciples,
none goes by the name Changgeng.
It must be rumors getting twisted
along the way.
Detached Master,
don't waste your tricks on me.
Your sect produces a talent like this once in a thousand years.
You're afraid I'll poach him,
so you hid him,
right?
- We...
- Enough.
Since you've chosen to deceive me,
you think I'd still believe you?
You can't hide him forever.
If I can't find Changgeng,
I'll just stay here.
Go, prepare a good room for me.
It must be clean.
If there's even a speck of dust,
I'll report to my mentor
that you slighted an Elucidating Aureate Immortal
and have your sect shut down.
Arrange a clean room for the cultivator.
Grandlord isn't even angry?
He's not even spitting blood?
Exactly.
Westdawn Sect has already acted.
The situation looks a bit troublesome.
But don't worry.
I still have a backup plan.
A backup plan?
In this world of cultivation,
there are Three Sects: Human, Elucidating, and Seizing.
Since the Human and Elucidating Sects won't work,
I just need to direct it
toward the Seizing Sect.
Senior.
What is it?
Zhao Gongming of the Seizing Sect is here.
Mentor wants us.
The Seizing Sect?
Got it. Go on ahead.
Sure!
I'll hang up now.
It's sour.
It tastes pretty good.
Do you want some?
The Seizing Sect
is a lineage of Heaven reach Master.
They take everyone as disciples.
That means
all beings can walk the immortal path.
Basically everyone.
Just look at them!
One after another,
freaks and oddballs.
What a bunch of half-wits.
Listen, you two.
Ascendance Sect is huge.
Don't go wandering off.
Especially you, lass.
The Grandlord is here.
Grandlord.
Sir,
what brings you here?
What was his name again?
What's he called?
Detached Master.
Old man.
You...
I hear Changgeng here survived
the Divine-Demon Tribulation.
I came to make his acquaintance.
We'll have dealings later.
Among all of our disciples,
there is no Changgeng here.
You must be too old to remember him.
He and I are of the same generation.
Brat, why like an old man?
You...
How about this?
We'll look for two days.
If we find him,
we'll leave.
If we can't find him,
we'll leave anyway.
We'll stay here for two or three days.
Arrange some accommodations for us.
There are so many of you.
So, make sure the place is big.
And food and drinks.
Just handle it.
Everyone,
let's eat and drink our fill here.
Okay?
Sure.
About the bill after...
Old man, write it down.
You're paying.
Let's go.
Grandlord.
Now you know, right?
Grandlord coughs blood all the time.
He never gets better.
Probably from anger.
All disciples, attention!
Zhao Gongming is a man
you must never cross.
Mark my words.
Yes.
Both the Elucidating and Seizing Sects are here.
If it were an ordinary man by now,
he'd have no way out.
You're a little rascal.
You're no ordinary man.
You understand me.
Since this world is divided into...
Lan Ling'e?
Though
there are Three Sects,
not just Three Sects can face the Tribulation.
That's the blind spot.
I just need to use it well
and steer Changgeng to the East Sea.
Senior.
Me again.
When will this end?
I'm Mermaid Princess Jiang Si'er,
leading the South Sea elites
to greet the elders of Ascendance Sect.
I heard Changgeng is here.
Changgeng isn't a disciple here.
Princess, look elsewhere.
Please house our Mermaid Clan guests.
[Hall of United Spirits]
Lan Ling'e!
I'm leaving.
Go on, hurry.
Shut it tight.
Keep it blocked.
Don't let anyone in.
What are you doing?
Mentor.
Mentor, many have come outside.
You must not open the gate.
Yes, so many people.
Nonsense.
We welcome immortal affinity.
If we shut our door
when too many come,
how do we take disciples?
Open the gate.
But Mentor, this...
Deity!
Close the gate.
Mentor,
why?
At this rate,
we'll be overwhelmed.
Oh, no!
Please don't let Mentor find out
I stayed out all night.
Move.
Come on, have a taste.
Please keep things orderly and tidy.
Be sure to stay safe and keep clean.
Keep it clean, alright?
Beautiful, isn't it?
[I Was Here]
Still hungover?
The Human Sect.
So amateurish.
Jiu.
You're back.
Wu, what are you up to?
Such a lovely day today.
I just slept in.
I was about to take a stroll.
You're getting better at acting.
You were out
drinking all night, right?
Wu.
You mustn't tell Mentor.
Or he'll punish me again.
He made me do this
inside that circle
and forbade me from drinking
or even moving a bit.
- It was terrifying.
- Alright.
That man...
Alright.
Sit down first.
Really frightening.
Come on.
Here, have some tea.
To sober you up a bit.
I knew you treat me best.
Mentor is busy with outside affairs today.
He doesn't know you weren't in your room.
That's good.
But your drinking causes trouble.
What if you cause some serious calamity?
Let alone me.
Even Mentor couldn't save you.
But I still have you.
If not, I still have
all those seniors.
Jiu,
no matter what,
in the Ascendance Sect,
you count as an elder.
Since you are an elder,
you should shoulder that duty.
But I'm your junior.
Problems like these
are for my seniors to solve.
As for me, I should be carefree,
happy, easy, and at leisure.
Don't you agree?
You...
I think you should go to Jade Division.
Jade Division suits your temper.
You really get it.
Do you know how good
their wine is?
Those two at Jade Division...
What immortal seedlings are they?
As for Ling'e, she's so clever
and utterly adorable.
As for Changshou...
That little frame looks so frail.
And he cannot touch girls.
He can foam at the mouth with one touch.
I wonder if he's cured by now.
That sounds intense.
What is it, Wu?
Qi Yuan called them immortal seedlings.
He asked me
to look after them more.
No problem.
If anyone dares bully those two,
I'll fly over and strike with my sword.
Alright, you win. Happy now?
What I meant to say is
I'd like to bring these two
to our Griefbane Division.
What do you think?
I think it's a splendid idea.
You fetch them,
and I'll take charge of their discipline.
You? Discipline them?
How ridiculous.
Yes, I'll do the disciplining.
And I swear,
I'm not just after their wine.
Speaking of wine,
something just came to mind.
What?
To punish you, Mentor
ordered someone
to go to your quarters
and give away all your wine.
I may have sinned greatly.
But it shouldn't go this far.
How can he give away my wine?
Mentor, you white-haired old man!
- You're so mean!
- I knew you'd say that.
So,
I hid a jar for you.
Where is it?
In the backyard.
That's more like it.
I love you.
Remember: Don't let anyone see it.
Don't worry; It's fine.
Let me drink!
Mentor!
Drinking again?
It has nothing to do with me.
You're too cruel, Mentor.
[Quarters for the Sea Deity Sect]
Everyone.
Since you're not cultivators,
you cannot enter Ascendance Sect.
The Grandlord, understanding your quest,
has specially prepared food and water for you.
One serving of food per person.
Water is up ahead. Help yourselves.
Great!
Hand these out to everyone.
So, Changgeng the Great
is renowned across the cultivation world.
So many have come for his name.
How did I not know before?
I was a frog in a well.
Of course, you knew nothing.
It'd be odd if you did.
Where did Senior Changshou go?
He probably sought some quiet.
I see.
Free from outside distractions,
he stays true to his heart.
Senior Changshou has taught me another lesson.
Junior Ling'e.
I'll return to cultivate first.
Alright.
Ridiculous.
Today,
I will tell you a story
about a famous tale of our sect
between the Sea Deity and the Dragon Maiden.
That day,
the Sea Deity Changgeng...
Changgeng?
Was walking upon the surface of the sea.
- My senior?
- Suddenly,
in the distance, there was...
I won't listen! I won't listen!
Senior could never be that kind of person.
Impossible!
Let me tell you.
That carp spirit had a truly captivating figure.
Sea Deity Changgeng
was burning with desire.
He tore off his clothes,
revealing his muscular chest.
This is not for children!
I'm not listening!
Absolutely impossible.
Senior is nothing but a toad in the pond.
No one would ever be with him.
Oh, heavens! Oh, earth!
Impossible!
Blood again.
It's fine.
I'm used to it.
Mentor,
if I had your cultivation,
I'd be throwing up every day too.
Our sect
hasn't been this lively in ages.
Mentor, forgive my bluntness.
The Three Sects have long been at odds.
The Elucidating Sect is proud and arrogant.
The Seizing Sect is in disarray.
The Mermaid and Dragon Clans are linked.
When they're all here,
I've been busy
keeping order.
Exactly.
The Three Sects have long been at odds.
Yet we all came from one root.
And the Way we seek comes from one line.
Why must we fight each other?
I have a dream.
One day,
the Three Sects will drop their rifts
and gather under one roof
to cultivate the Way together.
We'll even
be united.
That
would be good,
but
is it possible?
This is my dream,
yet all this time,
I've been at a loss.
But now,
I see hope.
For the Three Sects to put aside old grudges,
they must face a common enemy.
A common enemy?
I...
Your cultivation is too weak
to tell from the divination.
I don't blame you.
Our sect has a destined fate.
A thousand years after its founding,
it will face a great calamity.
A great calamity?
What?
Since the founding of our sect,
it has been exactly a thousand years.
It's all right.
When the great calamity comes,
it will be hard for us
to get through it alone.
So, I had to let
so many stay here.
Someone faced Tribulation in the South Sea.
Why did everyone
end up here?
Don't you think
someone is setting this up?
Then,
do you mean
someone means harm to us?
I can sense a new force
rising beyond our walls,
though I don't know which force it is
or why it targets us.
But when the great calamity comes,
faced with a fatal peril,
I believe all the people present
can surely set aside past differences
and unite against the enemy.
I'll use our destined calamity
as the start of Three Sects' unity.
Mentor,
thanks for your guidance.
Come on, it's your turn.
My turn.
Ready?
Ready.
Let's go.
Sir.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Good, then.
Wang Qi?
There are many Wang Qis here.
Sir,
which Wang Qi are you looking for?
I'm looking for Wang Qi in Spiritkin Division.
Wang Qi from Spiritkin Division?
Is it accurate?
Yes.
Liu Sizhe.
Sir, what brings you here?
You are Liu Sizhe, right?
Yes.
Please bestow your guidance.
Guidance is not mine to bestow.
But if you insist, it's fine.
Then I'll bestow first.
After that, you can call.
Bestowed.
Call!
Seniors.
What are you doing here?
Junior.
Zhao Gongming, he's not human.
What happened?
Oh, right, Junior.
Hurry to Jade Division! Save them!
I'm here!
Are you all waiting for me?
Next.
Li Changshou of Jade Division.
Elucidating Sect.
Seizing Sect.
Mermaid Clan.
Bear Stockade.
Westdawn Sect's goal is clear.
It's Changgeng.
You still won't heed my plan.
Yunxiao.
Don't worry.
I won't force you.
I trust you.
You have your own plan.
Thank you, Yunxiao.
But you also promised me
that you'd tell me every plan.
I'm waiting for someone.
Waiting for someone?
To break Westdawn Sect's plot,
the safest plan
is still to send the Dragon Clan up
and let the Celestial Court step in.
But the key figure
is Ao Yi.
Yet the one he wants most to see
is Changgeng.
I see.
So, Westdawn Sect spread the rumor
that Changgeng was at Ascendance Sect.
And it worked in your favor.
You used it to bring Ao Yi here to Ascendance Sect.
Once he shows up,
I'll let him be
the Tribulation bearer
and help him build his name
to lead the Dragon Clan.
Then, he can go back to the Dragon Palace
to take the throne
and, in turn, root out
the Westdawn members hidden there.
Yunxiao, you are truly wise.
You saw through it at once.
So, that's your plan.
Very well, I'll help you.
Thank you, Yunxiao.
For now,
I only need to stay quiet
here in Jade Division
and wait for Ao Yi to show up.
But aren't you worried
that Westdawn Sect will find you first?
Don't worry, Yunxiao.
I've made thorough preparations.
I've withdrawn all paper butterflies.
Even if Westdawn Sect has immense power,
they'll never discover my location.
♪ See mortal joys and sorrows ♪
♪ Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds ♪
♪ Alas, love has many twists and turns ♪
♪ Memories filled with sorrow ♪
♪ Slowly, wishes turn to regret ♪
♪ You've gone afar, like mist fading ♪
♪ Tearfully, this life's bond is not over ♪
♪ Past fragments vanish into night ♪
♪ Down a few more cups of wine ♪
♪ Through land and sea, I ask you to come ♪
♪ For honor's sake, upright and grand ♪
♪ Alas, our story is short ♪
♪ Slowly, wishes turn to regret ♪
♪ You've gone afar, like mist fading ♪
♪ Tears fall, this fate's not done ♪
♪ Past fragments vanish into night ♪